Guide to the Romeyn Berry family papers, 1636-1960.
Berry, Romeyn family papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Romeyn Berry family papers, 1636-1960.
2531
Romeyn, Berry, 1881-1957.
11.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence includes personal and business correspondence; Berry's letters from Kenneth Roberts, E.B. White, and Allison Danzig; one letter from Major William B. Miles concerning the activities of the Seventh Regiment, New York National Guard; correspondence of Berry's second wife, Hester Bancroft Berry, her father, Wilder D. Bancroft, and other members of the Bancroft family. Writings include copy and clippings from his "Talk of the Town" columns in The New Yorker; articles from the Ithaca Journal and Cornell Alumni News; radio broadcasts; and books and pamphlets by others. Diaries and journals by Berry, Katherine Bott Bancroft, and Hester Bancroft Berry, 1943-1951; farm accounts from "Stoneposts," Jacksonville, N.Y., 1936-1938; drawings; family and other photographs; legal documents and related items referring to the Berry and Gould families; newspaper clippings relating to Professor Wilder D. Bancroft; items having Ithaca or local interest, including Lyceum Theater accounts, 1893-1923; and miscellaneous family items. Also, student scrapbook of Olive Nutting Berry at Wells College, with material about social events at Cornell University.
Also, correspondence between Romeyn Berry, his grandmother Hannah Wright Gould, his mother, and others, mostly when he was an undergraduate at Cornell; condolence letters after Berry's death, written to his widow Hester Bancroft Berry, to his daughter, Hilda Berry Sanford, and to Ruth Berry McDonald; program from the memorial stone dedication in 1988; magazine and newspaper articles; trust agreement; and typescript version of Hannah Wright Gould's 1871"Garden Journal," with a pen-and-ink drawing on wood of Romeyn and Harriet Berry as children.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Columnist, author, lawyer, farmer.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence includes personal and business correspondence; Berry's letters from Kenneth Roberts, E.B. White, and Allison Danzig; one letter from Major William B. Miles concerning the activities of the Seventh Regiment, New York National Guard; correspondence of Berry's second wife, Hester Bancroft Berry, her father, Wilder D. Bancroft, and other members of the Bancroft family. Writings include copy and clippings from his "Talk of the Town" columns in The New Yorker; articles from the Ithaca Journal and Cornell Alumni News; radio broadcasts; and books and pamphlets by others. Diaries and journals by Berry, Katherine Bott Bancroft, and Hester Bancroft Berry, 1943-1951; farm accounts from "Stoneposts," Jacksonville, N.Y., 1936-1938; drawings; family and other photographs; legal documents and related items referring to the Berry and Gould families; newspaper clippings relating to Professor Wilder D. Bancroft; items having Ithaca or local interest, including Lyceum Theater accounts, 1893-1923; and miscellaneous family items. Also, student scrapbook of Olive Nutting Berry at Wells College, with material about social events at Cornell University.
Also, correspondence between Romeyn Berry, his grandmother Hannah Wright Gould, his mother, and others, mostly when he was an undergraduate at Cornell; condolence letters after Berry's death, written to his widow Hester Bancroft Berry, to his daughter, Hilda Berry Sanford, and to Ruth Berry McDonald; program from the memorial stone dedication in 1988; magazine and newspaper articles; trust agreement; and typescript version of Hannah Wright Gould's 1871"Garden Journal," with a pen-and-ink drawing on wood of Romeyn and Harriet Berry as children.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Berry, Romeyn, 1881-1957.; Berry, Hester Bancroft, 1899-1963.; Bancroft, Wilder D. (Wilder Dwight), 1867-1953.; Bancroft, Katherine Bott.; Bancroft family.; Berry, Olive Nutting.; Berry family.; Gould, Hannah Wright, 1819-1912.; Sanford, Hilda Truslow Berry, 1916-; McDonald, Ruth Seely Berry, 1913-; Danzig, Allison.; Roberts, Kenneth Lewis, 1885-1957.; White, E. B. (Elwyn Brooks), 1899-1985.; Bancroft family; Bancroft, Katherine Bott; Bancroft, Wilder D. (Wilder Dwight), 1867-1953; Berry family; Berry, Hester Bancroft, 1899-1963; Berry, Olive Nutting; Danzig, Allison; Roberts, Kenneth Lewis, 1885-1957; White, E. B. (Elwyn Brooks), 1899-1985; Gould, Hannah Wright, 1819-1912.; Cornell University -- Students.; Wells College -- Students.; Lyceum Theater (Ithaca, N.Y.); Cornell University; Wells College
Titles:
New Yorker
Subjects:
Farms -- Jacksonville.; Families -- New York (State); Women college students.; Journalists.; Lawyers.; Authors.; Gardening; Authors; Families; Farms; Journalists; Lawyers; Students; Women college students
Places:
New York (State)
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Drawings.; Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Romeyn Berry
Legal Papers
Athletic Documents
Correspondence
Publications, Speeches, Broadcasts, and Plays
War Materials
Personal Material and General Documents
Cornell Material
Series II. Harriet V.V. Berry and Elizabeth Berry
Series III. Berry/Gould Family Material
Series IV. Hester Bancroft Berry and Wilder Bancroft
Series V. Olive Nutting Berry and Nutting Family
Series VI. Photographs and artwork
Series VII. Medals, Ribbons, and objects
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Romeyn Berry
  - Series Ia. Legal Papers
    - Application and registration of Romeyn Berry as Attorney, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Greene Consolidated Gold Company, La Brisca, 1897-1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Lee Nutting Estate, 1835-1889 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Indentures, property map, petition of Rebecca Wright regarding lands in Lancaster and York (1835)
    - Lee Nutting Estate, 1906-1918 (Box 1, Folder 3-9)
      Papers largely relate to Lee Nutting but include Arietta, Marcus Nutting, and others. Folder 5 includes photograph of unidentified woman.
    - Burke v. Underhill, 1903-1913 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Hunter, James v. Hudson, John, 1906-05 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Vaughan's Seed Store v. Stringfellow, 1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Vaughan's Seed Store larceny case, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Nutting v. The Joice Contracting Co., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Berry, Edward v. Bridgeport Transportation, 1908-1910 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Richmond Tax Matter, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Avebury Realty Company, 1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Truslow and Berry agreements, 1909-1918 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous legal papers, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Sacerdote v. Layman, 1911-1914 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bischof, Louis v. Schaeffer, Elizabeth, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Jones, Morgan estate, 1912-1914 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Rumsey and Co. v. Morey, L.A., 1912-1915 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Rumsey and Co. v. Travis, Walter W., 1912-1918 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Frelinghuysen, Theodore v. Howard, Francis, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - New York Yacht Launch and Engine Co. v. Erwin Jennings, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Prarie State Grain and Elevator Co., 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Fred Young and Co., Inc., 1913 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Cutler-Hammer Manufacturing Co., 1914 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Jackson v. Knapp, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mackenzie, Charlotte Documents, 1914-1917 (Box 2, Folder 10-19)
    - Maynard and Co. v. H.C. Mole, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Rumsey and Co. v. Charles Folcke, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Steen, Thomas, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Taylor, Short, and Kennedy, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Whinery, Samuel v. Berg, James and Cline, John, 1914-1916 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Feldman, Henry documents, 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - H.S. Vail and Sons v. F.R. McMullin, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Various agreements, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Bischof, Clara v. Straub, Frank and Anna, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Carew, Joseph J. v. Keefer, Daniel H., 1916-1918 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
    - Carew, Joseph J., 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Dean, Dorothy v. Hewett, Dexter, 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ennis and Co. v. Greenfield, 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Fertig, Henry v. Carew, Joseph J., 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Friedler, Rudolph v. Samuel Brody, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - McCulloch, George F., 1916 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Technology Sales Inc., 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Turner, J.R. and Effie savings, 1916-04-27 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Bancroft, Griffing v. Bancroft, Ethel, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Court Martial of Edward Burns Jr., First Provisional Battery, ORTC, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Caminsky, Benjamin, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Carew and Co. v. Perry Winckler and Co., 1917 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Carew and Co. v. Brand, Charles, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Chambers, Bernard, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dal-Brun, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Fullman, Arthur v. Ellis, George, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Gans, Leopold, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Gould, Sarah estate, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    - Hanover Brick Co. v. Kenny, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Hollander, C.H., 1917 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - The Life Saving Devices Co., 1917 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Mason, Norman v. Mason, Edith Barnes, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Marsalis, Thomas partnership, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Muller, H.B. v. Schmidt and Deery, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Pittsburgh Life and Trust Company, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Rowland v. Kirby, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Schafer, William, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Schmidt and Deery, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Philip D. Shapiro, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Hiram Sibley Estate, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Texas Medical Journal, Dr. Foregger, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Vezin estate, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Atlantic Motors Co., 1918 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Hewett Publishing Company, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Hyman Estate, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Subseries Ib. Athletics Documents
    - Documents and correspondence, 1906-1909 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Documents and correspondence, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      Includes scores and notes on track meets
    - Documents and correspondence, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      Includes scores and notes on track meets and corresopondence about track book
    - Documents and correspondence, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Documents and correspondence, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 40-41)
    - Documents and correspondence, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - A Brief History of Cornell Football from 1887 to 1924, typed, Undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Olympic Committee report of Gustavus Kirby, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Olympic Committee correspondence, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Event speeches, notes, and scores, 1914-1918 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1907-1917 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      Includes print of Shoellkkopf field and proposed stadium (1916), Entry Blank ICAAAA indoor meeting (1917), ICAAAA record of track meeting blank, college name placards, program 1917, Cornell-Penn 1907 football flier
    - Two photographs of Shoellkopf Stadium, one photograph of track race, Undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Athletics clippings and articles, Undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Intercollegiate Association of the Amateur Athletes of America 34th Annual Field Meeting, Soldiers Field, Cambridge Mass, 1909-05-28-1909-05-29 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Intercollegiate Association of the Amateur Athletes of America 39th Annual Field Meeting, Soldiers Field, Cambridge Mass, 1914-05-29-1914-05-30 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The National Collegiate Atheltic Association Proceedings of the 37th annual convention, 1942-12 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - First Annual Indoor Meeting of the Intercollegiate Association of Amateur Athletes of America program, 1915-03-06 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Program for dinner in honour of the Oxford-Cambridge Track Teams, 1929-07-20 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Scrapbook of clippings related to athletics, some by or about Berry, 1914-1919 (Box 10)
      Includes some invitations, programs, and publications like "The Winged Foot". Also includes handwritten loose speeches and articles. The back of the scrapbook has clippings on the Progressive Party, Berry's certification as attorney (1914), and a photograph of a Progressive Party banner with Berry running for assembly.
    - Cornell/Princeton statistics and score sheet, Undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Subseries Ic. Correspondence
    - Correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Copy of letter to Amos Dean Esq., 1829 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1876-1891 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Includes 1876 'stump recipe' and 1884 letter to Santa Claus, letters regarding fathers death
    - Bound letters to Romeyn from William B. Berry, 1892-1896 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      Content includes boat travel and trip out west.
    - Correspondence, 1895-1904 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Includes letters to and from Romeyn as a student at Cornell and letters about family deaths
    - Manuscript letter dated "Saturday," on Beta Theta Pi House stationery, in which Berry asks his mother's advice on whether to accept a job offer as editor of the Cornell Alumni News. At the upper left is a note in ink, "The plot thickens; please return.", 1900-1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1905-1909 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Includes 1907 letters with Bert Johnson regarding Ithaca Colored Band
    - Correspondence from mother, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1915-1919 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Includes legal correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1925-1930 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1932-1939 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Includes photocopies of letter from E.B. White (1937), information and correspondence on Hiram Corson's house
    - Correspondence, 1943-1949 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from Kenneth Roberts
    - Correspondence, 1950-1957 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Includes letters from Kenneth Roberts and booklet titled "Kenneth Roberts: biographical sketch, an informal study, his books and critical opinions"
    - Condolence letters and memorial statements, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Memorial statements and obituary, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - Correspondence regarding family cemetary upkeep and wills, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Subseries Id. Publications, Speeches, Broadcasts, and Plays
    - Publications
      - List of Romeyn Berry articles published since 1938, Undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - State and Tioga clippings, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17-20)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - State and Tioga clippings, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Reprints from State and Tioga, Undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Various articles by Berry, 1910-1950 (Box 4, Folder 41)
        Includes Accomodations for Visitors, Dee Day on the Dirt Roads, Memoirs of Push and Pull Football, campus confusion
      - The Widow, 1950-1954 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - The Alumneurosis, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Behind the Ivy, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Book jackets, related articles
      - Behind the Ivy, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Unbound book pages
      - Now, In My Time!, 1937-1957 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
        Includes handwritten copies
      - Dirt Roads to Stoneposts, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Stoneposts in the Sunset, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Reading Books for Fun, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Notes and comments for the New Yorker column, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Sport Stuff, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Scrapbook of "Sports Stuff" clippings, 1920-1926 (Box 10)
        Includes picture of Berry in boat, and signed copy of "Painting the Town Red" by TF Crane
      - Scrapbook of "Sports Stuff" clippings, 1927-1929 (Box 10)
        Includes some correspondence
      - Writin's About Country Life, 1936-1938 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Writin's by Rym Berry, 1936-1938 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - American Agriculturalist, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - American Agriculturalist, 1937 (Box 11)
      - The Big Red Team: A Football Song, 1905 (Box 11, Folder 4)
        Signed by Romeyn Berry
    - Publications not by Berry
      - Articles featuring Romeyn Berry, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 42)
        Includes article from the Princeton Alumni Weekly
      - Miscellaneous articles (Box 4, Folder 43)
        Includes Rochester Times article on Irene Castle and a pig pen lawsuit and "Berry Junction" by Alice Kline and Lila Jones. Some of the articles may have been written by Berry but no author is listed
      - The Ithaca Journal, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Pamphlets and booklets, 1907-1951 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        Includes Picture Taking with No. 3 Folding Pocket Kodak, The British Farmer at War, New York History, France History, Brief History of Jamestown Williamsburg and Yorktown
      - Pamphlets and booklets, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 3)
        Includes copy of Topography Maps of US, La Revue Moderne, FAO Schwarz catalog
      - Programs to various operas and plays, 1906-1915 (Box 9, Folder 4-6)
      - Sheet music, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Magazines, 1943, 1957 (Box 11)
        Life, Yank
      - Cornell Calendar, 1929 (Box MS, Folder 2)
      - Climate and Man, 1941 (Box 7)
      - The Plattsburger, 1917 (Box 7)
      - The Architectural Forum, 1923-07 (Box 7)
      - The Melodies Linger On, but Larry Freeman, 1951 (Box 7)
      - In Memory of Henry Williams Sage, 1898 (Box 7)
        With compliments of President Schurman
      - Retraints of Trade in Patented Articles, by Frank Gladney, 1910 (Box 7)
      - The Autobiography of Mary Emily Cornell, 1929 (Box 7)
      - Above Cayuga's Waters: A collection of articles and poems which have appeared in the Cornell Era, compiled by the class of 1917, 1916 (Box 7)
      - Era Cost and Stock Book of Drugs and Chemicals for Drug Buyers, 1897 (Box 8)
      - Enrollment of Voters in Tompkins County, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Speeches and Broadcasts
      - Speeches and articles, 1901-1950 (Box 5, Folder 12)
        Writings may be drafts of speeches or articles
      - Speeches and articles, 1901-1950 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Speeches, 1920-1950 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Radio scripts, 1940-1950 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - The Barnyard Gate broadcast, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - The Barnyard Gate broadcast, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
      - The Barnyard Gate broadcast, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
      - The Barnyard Gate broadcast, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Today and Yesterday broadcast, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Today and Yesterday broadcast, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Today and Yesterday broadcast, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Untitled writings, Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Plays
      - The President of Oolong: A Comic Opera in Three Acts, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Bright College Years: A Short Burlesque Helped Out by Song and Wassail, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Subseries Ie. War Materials
    - Documents and correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      Includes honorable discharge documents, US Gas School course certification, "Stunt Night" program, application for insurance, vaccination records, and some correspondence including grammar exercises from his children, Appointment to Sergeant certificate, paper certifying service (1957)
    - Lecture notes on chemical warfare gases, 1918-12 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Gas documents, orders, and bulletins, 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      Includes "Manual for the Use of Troops in Aid of the Civil Authority"
    - Certificates and discharge papers, 1918-1957 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - The Possibilities of Harmless Gases as a Weapon to be Used by the State Guard in Suppressing Riot and Civic Disorder, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook, 1917-1920 (Box 10)
      Contains documents, correspondence, and unidentified photographs of military men.
  - Subseries If. Personal Material and General Documents
    - Papers regarding 'father', 1889-1905 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Contains various newspaper articles and geneological pamphlets, focusing largely on James Romeyn, as well as a handwritten account (unsigned)
    - Romeyn Berry biography, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Hudson High School certificates, 1897-1898 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Bank statements and taxes, 1937-1956 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Romeyn Berry insurance whole life contract, 1927-08 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Romeyn Berry birth certificate, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Notebook including sketches, notes for Sport Stuff, Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Notes and ephemera (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Includes Spring Day 1929 invitation, silhouette, caricature, name cards, family material and invitations to events
    - Daily School Register for Ulysses, 1882-10-1883-09 (Box MS, Folder 2)
    - Memorial book for Romeyn Berry, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Subseries Ig. Cornell Material
    - Notebook of costs, notes for "The Widow" and events, Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Documents regarding alumni affairs and committee matters, 1916-1919 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      Includes legal agreements, event plan descriptions, and the Cornell Rubicon Song
    - Cornell miscellany, 1900-1915 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      Includes copy of the Cornell Deadly Sin spring day edition (1906), Beta Theta Pi programs, dance list and attendance, handwritten list fraternities with descriptions like "some angels are faithful" and " no sheep are carnivorous"
    - Cornell Dramatic Club script and programs for "Traffic Signals", 1934 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - William Robinson, ME 1906, reminiscences about Lyceum Theatre and plays, Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Bailey Hall performance programs, 1925-1928 (Box 5)
      Includes Percy Grainger, Russian Symphonic Choir (Basile Kibalchich), Boston Symphony Orchestra, Toscha Seidel and Arthur Loesser, Mischa Lebitzki, Dusolina Giannini (signed), The Cleveland Orchestra (signed, Nikolai Sokoloff), Harold Bauer, Ignace Jan Paderewski, Rosa Ponselle and Stuart Ross, Emilio de Gogorza and Helen Winslow, and Giovanni Martinelli (signed)
    - Reunion programs, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Cornell Extension Bulletins, 1931-1935 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Cornell Bulletin for Homemakers, 1929-1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Cornell pamphlets, 1907-1953 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Includes The Cornell Plantations 1953, John F Moakley: 40 years at Cornell, Alumni 27th annual dinner, President's Report, Pre-Cornell and Early Cornell (Part one signed by Albert Hazen Wright), Presentation Addresses the War Memorial, Corrnell Annual Horse Show, Savage Club Program and notes